RUPASMITA DEVI

EDUCATION

Trinity College Dublin - Dublin September 2020 To Present

Master's in Computer Science - Specialization in Data Science

Birla Institute of Technology and Science - Pilani, Rajasthan August 2014 to July 2018

Bachelor's in Computer Science

PROFILE

A current Data Science graduate student at Trinity College Dublin, I love computer science and Mathematics. Working as a software developer for more than 2 years, I have got handson with the in-demand trends of building APIs with microservices. parallel programming, Springboot, event-driven design development, CI/CD, logging, caching, etc. I love indulging in data-driven approaches to solve real-world issues and therefore I have decided to pursue graduate studies with an emphasis on Data Science.

I am looking for roles where I can contribute wholesomely to effective decision making, design, and development in building resilient services.

CONTACT

devi.rupasmita@gmail.com https://rupasmitadevi.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/rupasmi tadevi/

+353894185172

66 O'reilly Avenue, Dublin 8 - Y99F

ACHIEVEMENTS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Software Development Engineer - Tesco Bengaluru Pvt. Ltd. - Bengaluru, Karnataka July 2018 To August 2020

- Wrote critical functionalities for mobile microsite and grocery home shopping website to serve Tesco's online business.
- worked in mobile microsite's entire integration testing with consumers and downstream services, both in Pre-production and Production.
- Created a test framework using junit5 to test the enterprise APIs in a unified fashion.
- developed detailed monitoring dashboards and alerts for services on Splunk.
- enriched CI pipelines with features such as change-logs, plugins integrations (PMD, findbug, checkstyle), alerts, etc.
- Created a blue-green automation pipeline for a regulated and flawless live deployment.
- Hands-on with parallel programming and microservices.

Software intern - Paypal India Development Centre, Chennai, India - July 2017 to December 2017

- Worked on the backend implementation of Paypal packing slip and created the UI released in august 2017.
- Fixed various live bugs in Paypal packing slip.
- Created a shipping customer assistance portal to help customers with details on Paypal's postage services
- Used react.js for rendering the pages, also used JQuery, webpack, grunt and babel in order to deliver the project
- Project got accepted to be pushed into Paypal's live environment

IT Intern - Grasim industries, Madhya Pradesh, India - May 2016 to July 2016

- Created an online platform to maintain employee records and manage transaction between employee and office.
- Incorporated online services like conveyance booking and availing medical allowances in system for easy access.
- Used php and MySQL for backend, and html-5 and css-3 for frontend.
- Project got accepted to be merged with existing internal portal of the company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C, Java, Python, SQL, OpenGL, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Cypher (Query Language)

Technologies: Spring, AWS, Kubernetes, Project Reactor, Docker, Kafka, Couchbase, Redis, Istio, Apigee, Splunk (SPL)

Application Software: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe After Effects, Illustrator, Neo4j

Operating Systems: Ubuntu, Windows

Tesco, Bengaluru, June 2019: Secured the third prize in the India Edition of the annual Tesco Global Hackathon conducted across all colleagues and suppliers from all over the globe.

BITS, Pilani, March 2015: Won the Zonal Round of Design and Animation during Robothlon-2015 conducted by Robosapiens Technologies Private Limited.

Assam, May 2014: Secured State Rank 1 in the 12th Board of Assam Higher Secondary Education Council (AHSEC) in the Science stream.

Assam, June 2012: Secured State Rank 5 in the 10th Board, Board of Secondary Education Assam (SEBA).